every workplace is made of many but
seeks to work as one we achieve this
when we accept diversity Empower equity
and encourage inclusivity but our biases
can destroy it all here the only way to
win over biases is to learn to spot it
so that we can stop
[Music]
it
this is not a fire
drill but one to prepare us against
something just as dangerous an invisible
fire that can challenge the unity of any
organization today we'll do a simple
experiment and by the end of it you'll
find out what it is may I request all of
you to please join me
here today today I'll describe a few
situations that can happen in any office
and if you faced these ever at any point
in time in your career whether here or
in any other organization please step
forward and drop a ball here the first
question that I have for you here
is have you been treated unfairly by
your manager or colleague based on your
gender a statement like oh you're a guy
you're the perfect fit for on ground
field work or you're a girl you're not
the right fit for field
[Music]
workk ever seen a colleague getting
preferential treatment from a senior
because they're both from the same state
were you ever wrongly denied a promotion
because of your cultural background or
got labeled basis your home
state slowly but surely the biases
people faced in their careers came to
light some were treated unfairly because
of small town routs some treated
differently as they lacked a command
over
English biases even led to valid
opinions and ideas being overlooked
there were times when seniority was
celebrated over pure
Merit and when familiarity led to
bias there were those who were yelled at
publicly by a manager instead of
constructive criticism given privately
some were judged for their personal
choices and appearance like having
tattoos
piercings and some unfairly judged for
setting clear boundaries between
personal and professional life
can we have a big round of applause for
those who responded so
[Applause]
[Music]
bravely but now it is time for a braver
bunch of people to step
[Music]
forward if you feel you were ever
responsible for any of these situations
that we've heard today please step
forward and drop a ball in the other
jar it's not easy but after all we are
all
human so consciously or unconsciously at
any point of your career if you feel
your bias C the better of you then
please come
forward it takes great strength to admit
that you faced bias but it takes greater
strength to admit that you have been
responsible for it we can all see the
imbalance this imbalance is the result
of conscious and unconscious biases that
we all have within us and if we don't
admit it this can spread like a fire and
damage any organization this is the
reality of many work places today but we
can change it simply by admitting to our
biases within because understanding the
biases within us is the first step
towards a diverse Equitable and
inclusive
workplace
employe I was kind of looking into a
mirror and not a good part of
[Music]
myself what I'm taking away if something
going wrong around me I will speak up
about
[Music]
[Applause]
it